A Guide to the Margaret M. MacGill Photograph Collection on the O’Meara Family, 1915-1983
Virginia Room, Fairfax County Public Library
The Margaret M. MacGill Photograph Collection on the O’Meara Family, 1915-1983
Fairfax County Public Library
MSS 07-24
.25 linear feet
The Margaret M. MacGill Photograph Collection on the O’Meara Family consists of .25 linear feet and spans the years 1915-1983 and contains photographs and a negative.
MacGill, Margaret M. (1919-2008)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None
Acquisition Information
Gift of Mrs. Margaret MacGill on October 16, 2000
Additional photographs donated by her on December 15, 2004
Historical and Biographical Information
Margaret M. O’Meara was born on March 5, 1919 in Washington D.C. to Ernest C. and Bertha M. Beach O’Meara. She grew up at 528 Taylor Street, NW, however the O’Meara and Beach families had previously lived in Fairfax County, Virginia for three generations. She graduated from Roosevelt High School and the Washington School for Secretaries and began a life-long career as a military secretary. Margaret married Leon H. “Mac” MacGill on March 4, 1950 in Washington D.C. and the couple resided in Arlington, Virginia. An avid genealogist, Margaret published two books on her family’s history, “The Beach family of Virginia and the Voorhees family of New York and Virginia” in 1996 and “The O'Meara family of Virginia and the Lynch family of Maryland and Virginia: including collateral lines of Gossom and Maddox” in 1997. She died in Arlington on February 8, 2008.
Scope and Content
The Margaret M. MacGill Photograph Collection on the O’Meara Family consists of .25 linear feet and spans the years 1915-1983 and contains photographs and a negative. Subjects include the O’Meara family, the O’Meara family household in Merrifield, Fairfax County, Va., and scenes from Herndon, Va. and Washington D.C.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Margaret M. MacGill Genealogy Collection, Alexandria Public Library Special Collections, Kate Waller Barrett Branch Library
Margaret M. MacGill diaries and scrapbook, 1944-1949, Historical Society of Washington D.C.
None
Index Terms
Herndon (Va.); Merrifield (Va.); MacGill, Margaret M. (1919-2008); O’Meara family; Washington (D.C.)
Container List
- Katie O'Meara and Millie O'Meara (taken at 528 Taylor Street, N.W. Washington D.C.), Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Bessie O'Meara (taken at 528 Taylor Street, N.W. Washington D.C.), Undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Valenchia Costello O'Meara, Undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Albert Buckley O'Meara Home, Merrifield, Fairfax County, Va., Undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Albert Buckley O'Meara, Catharine Amanda (Kerns) O'Meara, Bessie Augusta O'Meara, William Alfonso O'Meara, Matrona Columbia O'Meara, Annie Elizabeth O'Meara, and Mildred Virginia O'Meara, Undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Bessie Augusta O'Meara, Mildred Virginia O'Meara, Katie Eloda May O'Meara at family home in Merrifield, Fairfax County, Va., Undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Mildred Virginia O'Meara and Katie Eloda May O'Meara, Undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Bertha Mae (Beach) O'Meara at 528 Taylor Street, N.W. Washington D.C., c. 1959 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Mildred Virginia O'Meara and Katie Eloda May O'Meara, Undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Katie Eloda May O'Meara, Undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Ernest Costello O'Meara and Bertha Mae Beach (wedding photo), 1915 June 30 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Bertha Mae Beach, Undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Albert Buckley O'Meara family and Kearns family, Undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Town of Herndon before the fire [photo and negative], Undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Margaret Marie O'Meara, c. 1923 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Bertha Mae (Beach) O'Meara, Leola Turner, Ernest Costello O'Meara (taken in backyard at 528 Taylor Street, N.W. Washington D.C.), c. 1933 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Margaret O'Meara and Bertha Mae (Beach) O'Meara marching in Fourth of July parade, corner of New Hampshire Avenue and Taylor Street, N.W. Washington D.C., c. 1923 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- House at 126 F Street, N.W. Washington D.C., Undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Bertha Mae O'Meara and nurses of Margaret O'Meara, 1919 May (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Margaret O'Meara and nurse, 1919 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Ernest Costello O'Meara, Bertha Mae O'Meara, and Margaret O'Meara in baby carriage at Court House in Washington D.C., 1919 May (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Miss Emma Ellmore, Mrs. Virginia (McFarland) Greear and Miss Elizabeth Ellmore (taken at the Ellmore's home at Herndon, Va.), 1983 July 26 (Box 1, Folder 22)